

**INFO** 

E-mail alan.nair@ed.ac.uk

Website alannair.github.io

# **ABOUT ME**

I landed in systems research after stumbling around various fields including software development, data science, and algorithmic trading while slowly realizing that my aptitude and natural interests align with computer systems. In particular, I love (and am experienced in) OS (esp. kernel hacking), Cloud Computing and Computer Architecture.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### RESEARCH INTERN

Sep 2022 -Dec 2022

Intel Labs | Bengaluru, India

- Successfully scaled Data Access Monitoring to terabyte-scale workloads
- Incorporated page table based profiling schemes to DAMON in the Linux kernel
- Evaluated performance gains on terabyte-scale memory workloads

# **RESEARCH INTERN**

May 2021 - Jan 2022

Intel Labs | Bengaluru, India (Remote)

- Built far memory support for serverless / FAAS environments using Linux kernel tools
- Integrated the far memory with the page fault handler
- Evaluated performance on standardized workloads
- Patented by Intel

## **TUTOR AND TEACHING ASSISTANT**

Aug 2020 -Apr 2022

# IIT Kanpur & The University of Edinburgh

- IIT Kanpur: Fundamentals of Computing Tutor. Tutored for two fresher undergrad batches over two semesters in 2020-21. Conducted weekly tutorials for programming in C, designed problems for labs and set questions for quizzes.
- IIT Kanpur: Operating Systems TA. Designed assignments, graded quizzes and resolved doubts for junior undergrads in 2021-22 Fall.
- IIT Kanpur: Compilers TA. Designed assignments, graded quizzes and resolved doubts for junior undergrads in 2021-22 Spring.
- The University of Edinburgh: Operating Systems Tutor. Tutoring for two junior undergrad batches. Conducting weekly tutorials.

# **QUANTITATIVE STRATEGIST INTERN**

May 2020 - Jun 2020

**Quadeye Securities LLC** | Gurugram, India (Remote)

Analysed real stock-price data and designed trading strategies

# DATA SCIENCE / SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT INTERN

May 2019 - Jul 2019

Monet Analytics | Gurugram, India

- Eye-Tracking and Detection over a webcam feed for a website
- Sentiment Analysis on tweets and user comments

# **PUBLICATIONS**

# Research Papers

- N. Alan, Sandeep Kumar, Aravinda Prasad, Ying Huang, Andy Rudoff, and Sreenivas Subramoney (July 2024). "Telescope: Telemetry for Gargantuan Memory Footprint Applications". In: 2024 USENIX Annual Technical Conference (USENIX ATC 24). Santa Clara, CA: USENIX Association, pp. 17–33. ISBN: 978-1-939133-35-9. URL: https://www.usenix.org/conference/atc24/presentation/nair.
- N. Alan, Raven Szewczyk, Donald Jennings, and Antonio Barbalace (Dec. 2024). "Near-Storage Processing in FaaS with Funclets". In: 25th International Middleware Conference (MIDDLEWARE '24). Hong Kong, Hong Kong: ACM, pp. 17–33. ISBN: 979-8-4007-0623-3/24/12.

#### Articles

**N. Alan**, Sandeep Kumar, and Aravinda Prasad (2024). "Telescope: Profiling Memory Access Patterns at the Terabytescale". In: *Usenix*; *LOGIN*; URL: https://www.usenix.org/publications/loginonline/telescope-profiling-memoryaccess-patterns-terabyte-scale.

# **EDUCATION**

Ph.D 2023-

**Dept. of Informatics, University of Edinburgh** | Edinburgh, Scotland

• Supervised by Dr. Antonio Barbalace and Dr. Boris Grot

## B.Tech + M.Tech (Dual Degree)

2017-2022

Dept. of CSE, IIT Kanpur | Kanpur, India

- CGPA: 8.7 / 10.0
- Masters Thesis: "Speeding Up Inference on CNNs for CPUs" was supervised by Dr. Swarnendu Biswas and done in collaboration with Dr. Sasikanth Avancha and Dr. Kavitha Madhu from Intel Labs, Bengaluru

## **ACHIEVEMENTS**

# Rankings

- All India Rank 189 in JEE Advanced 2017
- All India Rank 1067 in JEE Mains 2017

## **SERVICE**

# Artifact Evaluation Committee

ACM/IEEE MICRO 2023